Dennis Bruggink

12/09/1995

Telephone: +971 55 446 6573 (Mobile) Email: djls.bruggink@gmail.com



Professional Profile

A dedicated driven individual passionate about every aspect of engineering is fulfilling a lifelong dream to enter into the aerospace industry. Completing an accredited course in aeronautical engineering at the University of Salford obtaining practical and theoretical skills within the field, furthermore, expanding proficiency within applied engineering mathematics and analysis. Multilingual in three languages and raised across several European cultures, this self-starter developed a global perspective as a leader and organizer of the International Award (Silver) and Team Leader of the World Challenge guiding an expedition to build sustainable communities in Africa. Turning a dedication for physical endurance into a collaborative effort to absorb multiple ethnicities is indicative of how this go-getter seizes every opportunity to further his goal. Having recently completed seven months travelling through two continents and five countries it is clear that skills for international relations are at the top end of the boundary. This determined individual is very focused on completing his goals and operating in a world without borders as an impetus for entering a career in engineering innovation. Currently obtaining capable and applied knowledge of finance and equity management through day trading, also, improving my knowledge of coding languages through completing multiple courses on Udemy.

Objective

Gaining valuable experience within the aerospace and defence industry. Seeking an internship or an entry level job in a respectable company that excels in their aeronautics operations and are driving the industry forward.

Career Summary

Aug 2018 – Independent Forex Trader

Present

Developing a functional day trading strategy Discipline in maintaining specific strategy Patience and confidence in your own system Adaptability due to the forever changing markets

Mental toughness and stamina due to the possibility of high risk and volatility

Mathematical Analysis

Constant positive thinking and forward movement.

April 2018 -Sep 2018

Quantum Lux (Startup)

Introducing potential clients to our services

Maintaining a business-oriented relationship with all potential clients

Advise and consult clients on their best possible decision ensuring a satisfactory service

Database and statistical management

Producing extensive presentations underlying our decisions and methods

Producing and negotiating the most beneficial deal International client database through extensive marketing

Extensive work, preparation and innovative thinking to start a company

2014 – 2017 Aeronautical Engineering Student

Performance analysis of an F-16 Fighting Falcon

Completing lab reports Maintaining lab equipment

Applying lab health and safety procedures

Writing technical reports

Applying theoretical knowledge to practical scenarios

Completing a flight-testing course Integrating into a University lifestyle

Taking part in multiple societies and sporting teams Attending a busy lecture and workshop schedule

Extracurricular Experiences

October 2017 April 2018

Travelling - Dubai, Australia, Thailand, Korea, Japan

Improving international relations and resourcefulness in different countries

Implementing myself confidently in a country other than my own Experiencing foreign infrastructures and political systems

Working in multiple, different high intensity jobs. EG Labour work in Australia

Exploring different cultures and customs

Maintaining a budget and ensuring that money was allocated correctly

Putting myself out of my comfort zone day by day and overcoming all problems

2013 May - July

Team Leader, World Challenge (Swaziland, RSA, Mozambique)

Led expedition to three Southern African countries,

Organized expedition

Prepared 20 fellow volunteers

Planned and executed fund-raising activities

Constructed vegetable gardens and cooking facilities for Neighbourhood Care Points

Education and Qualifications

Level

Subject

Bachelor of

Aeronautical Engineering (BEng)

Engineering

University of Salford

3 A Levels

Maths, Physics and Economics.

5 AS Levels

Further Maths, Maths, Economics, Physics and Chemistry

11 IGCSEs

Maths, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, Business, English, Spanish, French, PE, IT and Music

Key Skills

I.T. Skills:

Microsoft Office: Word, PP, Publisher etc.

Skilled presentation producer Detailed and efficient report writing

Solidworks

Python

AutoCAD MatLab

HTML, C++

Javascript

MS Excel Advanced

Java

Languages:

Fluent: English Spanish, Dutch

Negotiation: French, German

Personal Details

Driver, clean license

Interests and Activities

Rugby and football (team captain), flying, sky diving, hiking, scuba diving, travelling and composing music